<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hello World</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 22:51:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Aug 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 22:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of orientation today. We woke up early, dressed in professional clothing, ate breakfast, and traveled to the State Department. We were all exhausted, but we dragged ourselves through the two layers of security. While waiting in the line, Julien (our ODI representative, original from Cologne, Germany) chatted with us about his experience. He can speak German, French, and English, in that order of proficiency, which is very impressive because his English is very good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 July 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 21:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/</guid>
      <description>I had my first day of orientation today. Overall, the program so far feels very haphazard. We had a packed orientation schedule that consistently went over time. We were given information incredibly late. There was an incredible amount of repetition in the information we were hearing (though I suppose I understand this). I have hopes for tomorrow, however, because we are visiting the Department of State.&#xA;Today, we sat in a circle and introduced ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 July 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/</guid>
      <description>Though the Olympics ceremony may be overkill and a waste of resources, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile to appreciate the worldwide culture of the games. On screen, every competing country gets its share of the limelight. The United States and France and Australia arrive in their massive boats, crowded with athletes, but they get the same few seconds as smaller countries that are less recognized. I am not from Belize, Liechtenstein, Nauru, or Somalia (the countries sending the fewest number of athletes, just one each), but I still felt an overwhelming sense of pride watching them excitedly wave their flags.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 July 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 19:28:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/</guid>
      <description>A cup with a Maryland flag, surrounded by black-eyed Susans, is sitting on my desk. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for it to dry until I can glaze it with modge-podge, pack it between a few sweatshirts, and put it in my checked bag so I can gift it to my host family twelve days from now. I have Maryland-themed hats, keychains, and a lanyard, but nothing personal to me. I might bring spices to make a savory dish or a cup of chai.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 July 2023</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:47:41 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Reed-making is so artistic. You start with the cane (which must be gouged and shaped to even be usable) and soak it. Once it is thoroughly soaked, it can be folded over a mandrel, tied, and clipped. When tying a reed, every revolution of thread around the cane must be carefully placed. There must be no gaps between threads, so the thread must be held taut, but not too taut to break or fray the thread.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
