<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:28:51 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>3 Aug 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-3-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:15:47 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-3-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-3-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;Again, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this in retrospect because I want a record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the plane landed, it was roughly 7:50 am in Germany (and 1:50 am in Maryland). I was exhausted because I struggled to sleep on the plane. After landing, we all went to baggage claim to pick up our luggage. Immediately, I grabbed my small suitcase to check my oboe, and it was absolutely pristine. Not a crack nor a bent. It was shocking because even little bumps on the bus in elementary and middle school seemed to practically take keys off my instrument! I suppose it was well secured by the vacuum-sealed bag filled with clothes surrounding it. I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, we walked outside of the airport to wait for the bus. The first thing that struck me was how clean everything was. There was absolutely no litter on the ground. That, and all the signs being in German, were clear indicators that we were indeed in Deutschland. It&amp;rsquo;s a little funny because I kept forgetting that we were in Germany until we&amp;rsquo;d stumble upon a new sign in German. Trey (from Iowa) and Jen (from Georgia) wanted some soda, so Alex (from Pennsylvania) and I accompanied them just because we wanted to do something other than wait for the bus. In flawless German, Trey ordered his soda, and Jen followed his example. In Trey&amp;rsquo;s hometown in Iowa, many people speak an Iowan dialect of German, so he is very well-versed in German grammar, which in my opinion is the hardest part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, we walked a half mile to the bus, where we had a heated debate about the best condiments. Midway through the discussion, everyone kept accidentally falling asleep in turn. We were very tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got to the AiB, we were given refreshments and our host families picked us up. Regina and Udo greeted me and took my suitcases for me even when I insisted (in German) that I could take them myself. They took me to Friedensplatz, which is nicht so weit from AiB, and we took bus 550 to Mondorf Beckergasse, a station only 150 feet away from their house. I tried speaking as much German as I could, but I kept stumbling. They were very patient with me and waited for me to finish my sentences before responding. They also don&amp;rsquo;t know much English, so whenever I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand the meaning of the word, we had a whole conversation about it. It was very interesting to hear the definitions in German. I like finding synonyms for words. Etwa and fast both mean &amp;ldquo;nearly&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;approximately.&amp;rdquo; I would try and think of more examples but I can&amp;rsquo;t right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Regina&amp;rsquo;s house, there was another exchange student on his last day there. He also speaks English of course, but much better English than me. From there, Regina&amp;rsquo;s mother, brother, and nephew visited. They speak incredibly rapid German, and the other exchange student (Liam, I believe, from Cleveland) was able to easily respond, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t follow. I could only pick up on certain words. Sometimes, Liam would translate for me, or when questions were directed at me, they would slow down for me. I really appreciated it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we all piled in the car to visit Florian, Regina&amp;rsquo;s son. Florian has a wife Helene and a daughter Emilia. I had a gift for Emilia, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize she would be there so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring it. Regina assured me that Emilia and Florian and Helene would be visited her home though. We had small slices of seven or eight small homemade pizzas. They were all delicious, even the pizza with spaghetti. Before it was brought out, Emilia cried out, &amp;ldquo;Augen zu! Augen zu!&amp;rdquo; which means close your eyes. The spaghetti was the surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two hours I could hardly stay awake, so we all piled into the car again to take me home. At Regina&amp;rsquo;s house, I thanked them all and went to bed at about 10pm.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-3-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>2 Aug 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-2-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:00:02 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-2-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-2-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this all in retrospect, just so that I have a record for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, August 2, we woke up early for breakfast and final packing. I ate so many pastries from the dining hall in Georgetown before leaving to my room to make sure everything was packed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, we brought all our luggage into the front lounge of Copley Hall and Carrie gave us some final reminders for our year in Germany. Then, when that was over, Jordan (from Washington) brought out his cards and we played ERS. In the end, there was no clear winner because we had to leave, but I had more cards than Shane (from Alaska). Then, we loaded our luggage in the bus and toured the monuments. I was very tired, and we were basically given free reign of whether or not to stay in the bus or look more closely at the monuments. As much as I wanted to stay in the bus and take a nap, I knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see these monuments for a long time, so I dragged myself out of my seat. We visited the Korean War Memorial, which I don&amp;rsquo;t remember having visited before. It is very well designed, with soldiers marching at different locations, their eyes empty. There was a ring with the names of the soldiers who died in the war. There were so many names; it was unbelievable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, we traveled to the Pentagon mall where Carrie gave us 20 dollars each for lunch. I scarfed down Panda Express with my friends while they debated over boba flavors. From there, we traveled to Dulles airport. My checked suitcase was exactly 50 pounds&amp;mdash;just at the limit, right before I would need to pay a hefty fine for overweight luggage. Then, brought our carry-on luggage to the correct gate to board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After playing a quick game of American or European (the Europeans tended to be dressed better and put together more, while the Americans were more likely to be dressed in pajamas and more comfortable clothing), we began to board. But while I was in line, I was told that I would need to check my suitcase&amp;mdash;the one with my instrument in it&amp;mdash;and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take it out. I asked them if I could and they refused, and though I understand that they had a tight schedule to follow, they spoke to me very impatiently. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but cry a little, thinking about how my oboe would fare in the temperatures or the bumping. I finally settled in the seat, comforted by how the oboe was fixed in place by all the clothes in the bag, and the flight attendant walked around to give us headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my friends in the row next to us, Phoebe (from Alaska), Alex (from Pennsylvania), and Kenzie (from South Carolina), a the attendant spoke in German. I understood it perfectly&amp;mdash;very few words were spoken. But then, she turned around, made eye contact with me, and switched to flawless English. I was too surprised to even say &amp;ldquo;danke schön.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenzie, having seen the interaction, smiled and said in her classic Southern accent, &amp;ldquo;Baby, I think you just got profiled.&amp;rdquo; It was funnier than it was insulting. To be fair, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know much German!&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-2-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>1 Aug 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 22:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of orientation today. We woke up early, dressed in professional clothing, ate breakfast, and traveled to the State Department. We were all exhausted, but we dragged ourselves through the two layers of security. While waiting in the line, Julien (our ODI representative, original from Cologne, Germany) chatted with us about his experience. He can speak German, French, and English, in that order of proficiency, which is very impressive because his English is very good. He spoke in German with some of the diplomats at the State Department and it was very encouraging because I could easily understand what they were saying even though they were speaking at a normal conversational pace. It took me a second to process and translate the German into the English, but I got it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went into the meeting room and sat in a circle. Our first section was discussing embracing other cultures and culture shock (renamed as cultural adjustment) and how we&amp;rsquo;d react to that. The general gist was that culture shock occurs because your expectations/norms don&amp;rsquo;t align with the culture around you. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that will affect me, because I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in the sanctuary of my home where everything is constant. This will be a very new experience for me. We then participated in a diplomacy nation, where we each represented a different fake country. We were Budan, a country that was passing laws persecuting a minority group (though we justified it by saying that since those minorities were economically successful, they must be using unfair business practices). The minorities of this group were fleeing to a neighboring country, Gilbia, though the number was so great that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t support all of them. Budan was clearly in the wrong, but we still had to fight for our side. I was the representative for our side and I emphasized all the good things and denied the Budanese government&amp;rsquo;s involvement in the crisis. It was an interesting exercise and somewhat uncomfortable to argue so strongly for a position we did not agree with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we spoke to a diplomat who had gone through similar experiences with her job. She&amp;rsquo;s a very tough lady. She joked and laughed with us, but by the way she was talking, it was clear that she was well-read and she knew what she was doing. She told us that she almost resigned once because she had to fight for a position that she didn&amp;rsquo;t believe in, but then she chose to stay because she decided that it was probably better to stay and advocate for what she really believed in. This is why I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could do law; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could take fighting for a position I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in. It would eat at my conscience. I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s why so many foreign service people resign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we continued our discussion on culture shock, and then departed. From there, we had some free time, so I walked with some others to a boba shop. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any, but it was interesting to speak with some of the others on their backgrounds. Trey (from Iowa) is interested in welding, and he&amp;rsquo;s going to MIT for welding after this year. Alex (from Pennsylvania) is interested in medicine, but she hopes to explore other fields as well to make sure she really wants to do medicine. It was fun to explore the DC area and figure out the directions by using Google Maps as little as possible. Some people there who are accustomed to things like public transport found it very easy to navigate. This other girl Braidyn (from Utah) and I did not find it so easy, but they will be giving us a presentation on transportation in Germany, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too worried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we had dinner. We moved into the lounge and I brought cards, so after we ate pizza I brought everyone together to play Spoons and Slapjack. Brent (from Wisconsin) won Spoons and I won Slapjack. It was fun because all awkwardness just completely disappeared. Everyone was just intensely fixated on winning. It&amp;rsquo;s the main reason I love card games: it&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate tool to bring people together without too many resources. Ruby (our CBYX mentor, from Minnesota) said that she brought two decks, so we can play more cards games at the airport tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, we were weighing our luggage and packing anything we needed to pack. Before my suitcase was weighed, I asked all the people in the room if they wanted to predict the weight. Remembering the chocolates in my suitcase, I promised chocolate to the person who was closest. It was fun! I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect so many people to join in but chocolates seemed to motivate everyone. Even one of the mentors (Zach, from California) and Carrie joined in. Zach ended up coming in second place, but Andrew (from Illinois) won. He ended up passing out the chocolates to everyone anyway. I love how easy it is to do little things to bring these groups together. Everyone is very friendly and looking for friends.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/aug-1-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>31 July 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 21:15:02 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;I had my first day of orientation today. Overall, the program so far feels very haphazard. We had a packed orientation schedule that consistently went over time. We were given information incredibly late. There was an incredible amount of repetition in the information we were hearing (though I suppose I understand this). I have hopes for tomorrow, however, because we are visiting the Department of State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we sat in a circle and introduced ourselves. We have a roll call system where each of the 25 of us is assigned a number. When Carrie calls out, &amp;ldquo;Sind wir alles da?&amp;rdquo; (Are we all here), then Jordan Allen, whose number is 1, calls out &amp;ldquo;eins!&amp;rdquo; From there, the rest of us call out our number in German. It feels vaguely juvenile but I understand it. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier than taking attendance the way they would in school. 13 in German is &amp;ldquo;dreizehn,&amp;rdquo; which has two pronunciations: one with the rolled &amp;ldquo;r,&amp;rdquo; and one with the guttural &amp;ldquo;r.&amp;rdquo; My guttural &amp;ldquo;r&amp;rdquo; is still very French sounding, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been sticking to the rolled &amp;ldquo;r&amp;rdquo; for now, although German teachers have told me that it makes me sound more American in some regions of Germany. The last thing I want is for a German to switch to English because of a small pronunciation or grammar mistake, which apparently is very common!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We listened to two alumni speak about their experiences with the program. The first component is the language school. Generally from 8 am to 1 pm, it is packed with activities. Rather than take tests or memorize vocabulary lists, we will have more hands-on experience. One of the alumni recounted an experience when one of the lessons was on ordering food at a restaurant. Instead of giving them a list of phrases to memorize, he merely took the class out to order ice cream at a store. This is an interesting method because I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done anything like it before, mainly because I like to be overprepared for everything. However, I think small trips like these (and the other excursions we will take) will be important because it&amp;rsquo;ll teach me to thrive on underpreparation.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/july-31-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>27 July 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;Though the Olympics ceremony may be overkill and a waste of resources, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile to appreciate the worldwide culture of the games. On screen, every competing country gets its share of the limelight. The United States and France and Australia arrive in their massive boats, crowded with athletes, but they get the same few seconds as smaller countries that are less recognized. I am not from Belize, Liechtenstein, Nauru, or Somalia (the countries sending the fewest number of athletes, just one each), but I still felt an overwhelming sense of pride watching them excitedly wave their flags. I would love to be on those boats, because at that level, and in their position, they have nothing to lose and everything to gain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt a more personal sense of pride watching the Indian boat float by. Noting my reaction, my father asked me wryly, &amp;ldquo;Are you Indian, or American?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; I responded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smiling, my dad shook his head and gently corrected me. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re American.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I officially am American. It used to irritate me whenever my parents pronounced words incorrectly when it seemed so simple, or whenever they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the words to empathize with my stresses with school or other aspects of my life. I turned away from the plates of Indian desserts my mother made for me, choosing to eat an ice cream sandwich instead. I dragged my feet into my Telugu school classroom every Sunday for four years. But when I entered high school, I realized that I had missed out. I met a friend who introduces herself with the Indian pronunciation of her name, proudly proclaiming, &amp;ldquo;this is my real name, why should I change it to make it easier for other people?&amp;rdquo; I met friends who are well-read on Indian news and Indian geography, friends who effortlessly switch to the language they speak at home. I strive to be as Indian as I can by practicing my language, cooking with my mother, and learning Telugu songs and movie dialogues by heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied to my father, &amp;ldquo;You are American too,&amp;rdquo; reminding him of how he and my mother had switched from having an Indian to an American citizenship not long ago. Sometimes their small slip-ups still irk me, but then I remember how they have begun to release their hold on their Indian origins for my sister and me. I will never become Indian enough for them to stop Americanizing themselves in ways more than changing citizenships, but I want to try.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/july-27-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>23 July 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 19:28:43 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/ -&lt;p&gt;A cup with a Maryland flag, surrounded by black-eyed Susans, is sitting on my desk. I&amp;rsquo;m waiting for it to dry until I can glaze it with modge-podge, pack it between a few sweatshirts, and put it in my checked bag so I can gift it to my host family twelve days from now. I have Maryland-themed hats, keychains, and a lanyard, but nothing personal to me. I might bring spices to make a savory dish or a cup of chai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to the cup is a freshly packed bag of reed-making supplies, on a small towel covered in cane shavings. I learned how to tie reeds two days ago. I always hold my breath when I fold the soaked cane over a knife. From there, I alternate between measuring and shifting the position of the cane on the tube. When the alignment is perfect, my fingers must act like glue to hold the cane in place. I always end up wishing I had an extra hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began reading The Magic Finger by Roald Dahl in German today. It was one of my favorite books when I was younger, both because of its punchy, succinct writing style and the story itself. At that time, I had recently begun to learn about deforestation and its impact on animal habitats, so the idea of hunters getting their commeuppance was very apppealing to me. Though I am struggling through some of the German grammar and vocabulary, I am surprised at how much I remember. And my memory goes beyond the story; specific lines and scenes stand out to me, reminding me of their English counterparts. Once I finish The Magic Finger, I hope to tackle Matilda, which to me is a timeless story.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/july-23-2024/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>18 July 2023</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:47:41 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
        <description>Hello World http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/ -&lt;p&gt;Reed-making is so artistic. You start with the cane (which must be gouged and shaped to even be usable) and soak it. Once it is thoroughly soaked, it can be folded over a mandrel, tied, and clipped. When tying a reed, every revolution of thread around the cane must be carefully placed. There must be no gaps between threads, so the thread must be held taut, but not too taut to break or fray the thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my favorite part is scraping, though it&amp;rsquo;s misleading to consider all of scraping one step. The bottom of the reed is anchored between the index and middle fingers, and the hard cane is securely placed in the pad of your index finger. Then, with the thumb of that hand glued to the knife held by the other hand, you peel the hard, glossy bark from the surface of the reed, creating tiny, perfect coils of cane. Your thumb serves to push the knife down the reed, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t a tool; it is an extension of the knife itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the bark is peeled from both sides, you carve away more of the reed. The hard bark has been carved away, so you only need very light pressure to shape the cane under the hard top layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also must create two channels in the bottom half of the reed. By scraping both sides of each of the reed&amp;rsquo;s faces, and avoiding a line down the middle, you naturally create a spine. For a finished reed, when you hold it up to the light, the channels must glow. If the light shining through the channels isn&amp;rsquo;t bright enough, then you need to scrape more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the top of the reed, you also must create an upside-down V shape by angling the knife and pressing down. I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite gotten the hang of this step because I am more used to long, slow scrapes. And of course, this is by no means a comprehensive guide to reed-making I&amp;rsquo;ve skipped and glossed over many steps, because I&amp;rsquo;ve only really learned basic scraping so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though reed-making obviously serves a concrete purpose, I admire its artistic value. It is a skill that will allow me to pursue an artistic hobby (oboe playing), but it is just as artistic as music-making. It takes so much control and understanding to carve anything, let alone a playable carving.&lt;/p&gt;
- http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 